

# TRAN QUY PHONG (MR.)

## **SUMMARY**

Assisting a large number of foreign companies doing business in Vietnam in the past 6 years, I have a broad understanding of how tax fits into the wider business picture. My in-depth technical knowledge across from different types of tax (PIT, CIT, VAT, FCT, Customs duties) could help your company meet compliance responsibilities while seizing available tax saving opportunities.

My almost 5 years at Big 4 companies also develop my professional working style, foster curiosity to learn new things as well as a high sense of commitment and responsibility.

My career objective is to become an inspiring knowledgeable person whose expertise are not limited to taxation but also including finance, technology, good business senses and problem-solving skills.

Now, I am looking for a working environment which offers to learn onthe-job and exposure to every angle of business to achieve the above goals.

# **CONTACT**



+84 935 880 865



https://www.linkedin.com/in/phong-tran-3b7b2780/



quyphong91@gmail.com

# **EDUCATION**

#### ACCA

Upcoming (expected to complete in May 2020) Diploma & Certificate of IFRS

## University of Economics Ho Chi Minh City

Mar 2015 – May 2015 Chief Accountant Training

#### Da Nang University of Economics

Sep 2009 – June 2013 Bachelor of Financial Management

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Ernst & Young Vietnam Limited – Senior Tax Consultant

Nov 2016 - Feb 2019

- Work closely with Manager and/or Director in conducting tax compliance and advisory services, including but not limited to PIT, CIT, VAT, Trade & Customs for leading companies in Vietnam;
- Participate in due diligence for M&A transactions;
- Working with tax/customs authorities during tax/customs audit;
- Mentor and assist staff to discover and reach their full potential;
- Manage deadlines, team performance and clients' expectation;
- Developing effective relationships with clients and key contacts from relevant parties;

# KPMG Tax & Advisory Limited Branch – Tax Consultant

Oct 2014 – Sep 2016

- Participate in conducting and completion of human capital advisory and compliance services, such as payroll, PIT, compulsory insurance, work permit;
- Communicate effectively with Senior at each stage of conducting the above services; and
- Prepare necessary documentation for Senior's review;

# Olalani Resort & Condotel (Da Nang) – Accountant cum HR May 2013 – Feb 2014

- Verify and review the source documents;
- Manage and post accounting transaction into ERP systems;
- Ensure timely bank payment;
- Manage payroll and employees' records;
- Set up job interview schedule and join the interview with General Director; and
- Assist in launching ERP systems;

# **SKILLS**

